dzinearticles.com 2010-11-22

# Dzine Articles | Privacy Policy

One of the main policies of dzinearticles.com is to protect the privacy of its visitors. It is therefore our main objective to protect the data that you as a user provide us during the course of your interaction with us. Below is our privacy policy which we follow. This should give you a comprehensive idea of our method of collecting and using data we collect. 

Keeping the Membership information like name, address, e-mail ID, password, payment information, credit card information, telephone numbers, etc absolutely confidential is our top priority. Under no circumstances will these be shared with a third party. They will be used only to provide facilities and service as mentioned on our website. Information is collected during your registration on our site and on your specific requests for some of our services like entering a contest or signing up for a newsletter.

As a privileged user, your activities will be tracked on our site with its user tracking feature. If a necessity arises where we require to provide third parties who are not affiliated with Dzinearticles.com, with your personal information, for example in instances where you may accept offers posted by them on our website, it will not be done without your express permission

However, once you give us permission to provide them the information, you will then on come under their user privacy policy which may differ from our privacy policy. Dzinearticles.com will not be held responsible for information provided to third parties with your consent. 

### Why do we require your personal information?

Information collected from you is used by us to offer you content that is personalized. They are also used for sending features, e mails, newsletters, surveys, promotional mails and updates. As a user, you are always provided with the option of opting out of receiving such information. As a part of our self evaluation, we use information provided by you to administer and evaluate service offered by us. By monitoring the popularity of all the services offered by us, we identify the service that is most popularly utilized by our users.

Personal information provided by you is also used by us to provide you with offers from our partners. Your contact information will however not be revealed without permission. Information and offers from third parties thus are received and sent to users by Dzinearticles.com.

We help advertisers by identifying offers and information most relevant to our users. This is done by providing them with information including online usage, age and demographic. This way we are in a position to provide users with relevant and useful content. Again, no personal information about the user is revealed to the advertisers in these reports.

As a user, you are allowed to correspond by mail or send links to other parties. No e mail address, recipient or sender of these correspondences is retained by us. In such cases, pertaining to our responsibility of protecting our user’s safety, and our site’s integrity, we reserve the right to disclose information without any consent or notice to satisfy any regulations, law or requests from legal authorities. We will also disclose information in case of complaints from consumers, conduct official investigations or breaches of law.

Dzinearticles.com has no control over personal information provided by you voluntarily as you use services like forums, chat, bulletin boards, etc from other sites or from Dzinearticles.com.

### Our cookies

Every browser carries certain cookies which get attached to your computer when you visit a particular site. There is no personal information of the user stored in these cookies. They are used to track the popularity of our features and modify content on our site to your preference. As a user, you can either accept or decline these cookies by slight modification of your browser. Disabling cookies may however deny you access to some of our advanced features. 

### Updating personal information

As a user, you can visit the Member Center on Dzinearticles.com to update your personal information. If a user wants to opt out of promotional mailers and newsletters, it is possible to unsubscribe from these services by visiting the section called Newsletters in the Member Center. 

Training is provided to the staff of Dzinearticles.com to give top priority to the personal information provided by users. Personal information is stored in secure and controlled environments and only a very few employees have access to them. Security audits both external and internal are conducted periodically to ensure maximum security.
